A Guide to the Charles S. Worley, Jr., Collection, 1950-1982, undated
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Charles S. Worley, Jr., Collection
1950-1982, undated
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Worley, Charles S., Jr.
Ms1996-017
1.1 Cubic Feet 4 oversize folders; 7 boxes
The Charles S. Worley, Jr., Collection consist of architectural drawings of designs by Worley, done from the mid-1950s to the early 1960s, with several designs undated. The collection also includes a small group of photographs and negatives of Worley and his own residence in Blacksburg, as well as an extensive collection of slides documenting Worley's student and professional work, work of his students, his travels, nature, and images that were likely used as part of lectures.
Access Restrictions
The collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Charles S. Worley, Jr., Papers, were donated to Special Collections in September 1996.
Biographical Information
Charles Samuel Worley, Jr., was a Professor of Architecture at Virginia Tech from 1947 to 1982 and a Professor Emeritus from 1982 until his death in 1995. He received his B.S. in Architectural Engineering from the University of Oklahoma in 1936 and his M.S. in Architecture from the Illinois Institute of Technology in 1941.
Scope and Content
The Charles S. Worley, Jr., Collection consist of architectural drawings of designs by Worley, done from the mid-1950s to the early 1960s, with several designs undated. The collection also includes a small group of photographs and negatives of Worley and his own residence in Blacksburg, as well as an extensive collection of slides documenting Worley's student and professional work, work of his students, his travels, nature, and images that were likely used as part of lectures.
Scope and Content: Slide Inventory
A spreadsheet inventory of the slide topics, based on Worley's original organization, is available online.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by material type.
Related Materials
Herschel Gustave Anderson Elarth Papers, 1885-1988 (Ms1984-182). Finding aid available online.
Herschel Elarth-Charles Worley Architectural Firm Drawings (Ms2019-036).
Index Terms
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Faculty; Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.); University Archives; Virginia Polytechnic Institute
Genre and Form Terms:
Photographs
- Architectural Drawings, 1954 (Folder 1)
  - Offices and clinics for Dr. Richard A. Clay and Dr. C.W. McClure, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma; Winkler, Ried, & Boaz, architects (11 original drawings), 1954
  - Curtis Studios and Rainbow Travel Services, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma; Designed by Joseph N. Boaz (9 original drawings), 1954
  - Camp Meeting Grounds for Virginia Camp Meeting Association of the Church of God; Designed by Worley (8 original drawings), 1954
- Architectural Drawings, 1957-1959 (Folder 2)
  - Montgomery County Health Center, Christiansburg, Virginia; Designed by H.A. Elarth and Worley (14 original drawings), 1957
  - Blacksburg Redevelopment, Blacksburg, Virginia; Designed by Worley (10 original drawings), 1958
  - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Marcus L. Oliver, Blacksburg, Virginia; Designed by Shiver and Holland (8 original drawings), 1959
  - VPI Claytor Lake Camp and Topography Map, for YMCA. Pulaski, Virginia; Designed by Wells and Meagher, and Worley (2 original drawings), 1959
- Architectural Drawings, 1960-1962 (Folder 3)
  - Study Space, for Christian Church of Blacksburg, Blacksburg, Virginia; Designed by H.A. Elarth and Worley (3 original drawings), 1960
  - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Curtis Roane, Blacksburg, Virginia; Designed by H.A. Elarth and Worley (14 original drawings), 1961
  - Former Church Building adjoining Montgomery County Courthouse., Christiansburg, Virginia; Designed by H.A. Elarth and Worley (5 original drawings), 1962
- Architectural Drawings, undated (Folder 4)
  - Tremont Street Subway proposal extension, for Boston City Hall, Boston, Massachusetts (11 original drawings), undated
  - Addition to the Residence of Mr. & Mrs. Robert Fisher, Blacksburg, Virginia; Designed by Worley (5 original drawings and 5 copies), undated
  - Topography Map of Government Reserve Site, Reston, Virginia (1 original drawing), undated
  - Apartment building for Mr. and Mrs. Loren Hancuff, Blacksburg, Virginia; Designed by Worley (7 original drawings and 7 photocopies), undated
  - Addition to Store and Apartment Building, for Mr. R.F. Plank, Blacksburg, Virginia; Designed by C.H. Cowgill (2 original drawings), undated
  - Unidentified architectural drawings
- Slides, 1950s-1982, undated (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6, Box 7)
- Negatives (images of Worley and the house he designed for himself in Blacksburg), undated (Box 7)